RATHIJIT BISWAS, PH.D

CONTACT

9

Kolkata, India 700065

((D)

+919432976519,

>

biswas.rathijit@gmail.com

CORE QUALIFICATIONS

- Programming: C++, ROOT, Python (Pandas, Numpy, Seaborn, Matplotlib, Scikit learn)
- Predictive Modelling and Analytics, Machine Learning (Regression, Classification, Clustering)
- Statistics and Probability, Linear Algebra
- Tools: MS Excel, Power BI, Tableau, SQLite

CERTIFICATIONS

- Quantitative Researcher Virtual Experience Program by JP Morgan Chase & Co. on Forage
- Python for Data Science, offered by IIT Madras on NPTEL
- Foundations and Applications of Machine Learning, offered by IIT Kharagpur on NPTEL

NON-TECHNICAL SKILLS

Critical thinking, Performance under pressure and deadline, Collaborating mindset, Capabilities as instructor

AWARDS, HONORS AND ACHIEVEMENT

- Professor Shyamadas Chatterjee Award for Outstanding Scholar, 2019
- Served as the Junior Ambassador, India to the ALICE Collaboration, CERN, Geneva, 2016-2018
- GATE 2013 All India Rank 404

PROFILES

 LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/rathijitbiswas-ph-d-4127491b6 I have 9+ years of experience in qualitative and quantitative research and data analysis in global scientific collaboration. Passionate researcher with skills in Statistical Modeling, Monte-Carlo simulation and Machine Learning algorithms. Outstanding communication, organizational and leadership skills with proven record of 10+ publications in international journals with being reviewer of such two. I am looking for exciting opportunities in the industry as Quantitative Researcher/Analyst, Data Scientist to learn and deliver innovative solutions, with the ability to play as a team member or sometimes lead it, as I have done in my time in academia.

EXPERIENCE

October 2023 - Current

Machine Learning Engineer Intern Technocolabs Softwares, Indore

- Tools: Python, Jupyter, ML
- Developing a predictive PD model for a USA based P2P lending client leveraging ML
- Will also determine the allotted Rate of Interest (ROI) for individual customers

March 2022 - August 2022

Post-doctoral Research Associate, Institute of Modern Physics, Chinese Academy of Sc, China

- Tools used: C++, ROOT, Python
- Monte-Carlo simulation to optimize CEE-TPC detector pad design
- Learn and develop Machine Learning algorithms and data analysis techniques to infer qualitative & quantitative Physics messages from data recorded by the STAR experiment, BNL, USA

November 2013 - November 2021

Ph.D Research Scholar, Bose Institute in collaboration with ALICE, CERN, Kolkata/Geneva, India/Switzerland

- Tools used: C++, ROOT
- Develop algorithms to import, clean, cluster and correct large volume of data and perform quantitative and qualitative analysis to infer useful Physics messages from it.

EDUCATION

Certificate Programme, Applied Data Science (Pursuing) WorldQuant University, New Orleans, USA

2021

Doctor of Philosophy, Experimental High Energy Physics Bose Institute and CERN, Kolkata and Geneva

2012

Master of Science in Physics West Bengal State University, Kolkata

2010

Bachelor of Science in Physics (Major), Mathematics (Minor) University of Calcutta, Kolkata